Register to The Ernest Trow Carter Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music by Carter, 1879-1968; Series I; 13.75' (33 boxes)
  - Choral Works, I.D
    - [Is there one mosquito here?] Is there one mosquito here?: (Three-part Round) / By Ernest Carter., [1] sheet of music; 28 cm. (Box 26, Folder 216)
      With: My Dame hath a lame, tame crane (Four-part Round) / Old English (?)
    - [Jesus tender shepherd; arr.] Jesus Tender Shepherd: mixed voices / Music by Ernest Carter; Words by Mary L. Duncan; Third verse by Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1940 Nov., 1 manuscript close score (2 sheets); 24 cm. (Box 26, Folder 217)
      Two copies, note by Carter on first p. of one copy; offsets made Nov. 1940
    - [Jesus tender shepherd; arr.] Jesus Tender Shepherd / Ernest Carter., 4 manuscript parts; 16 x 24 cm. (Box 26, Folder 217)
      Parts include tenor I-II, bass I-II
    - [Jesus, tender shepherd; arr.] Jesus, Tender Shepherd: (For mixed quartet) / Ernest Carter. -- 1921., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 26, Folder 217)
    - [Jesus, tender shepherd; arr.] Jesus, Tender Shepherd: for Mixed Voices / Music by Ernest Carter (adapted from that of "Steps Song"). -- 1934-1940., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.) + 4 parts; 27 cm. (Box 26, Folder 217)
      Words by Mrs. Mary Lundie Duncan (third stanza by Ernest Carter)
    - [Jesus, tender shepherd; arr. (Sketches)] Jesus, Tender Shepherd., [2] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 26, Folder 217)
    - [Keep a-goin'] Keep A-Goin': (For Male Voices) / Music by Ernest Carter; Words from the Atlanta Constitution., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 218)
    - [Keep a-goin'; arr.] Keep A-Goin': Duet for two voices with piano accompaniment / Music by Ernest Carter; Words from Atlanta Constitution. -- ca. 1931 Jun. 15., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 33 cm. (Box 26, Folder 218)
      Note on first p.: Copy in B to Hindermeyer + Tuckerman - Jun 15/31
    - [Lawageela] Lawageela., 1 manuscript close score ([1] sheet) + 2 parts; 6 x 24 cm.-11 x 24 cm. (Box 26, Folder 219)
      Holographs in ink with pencil additions
      Includes alto and bass parts
      Sketch labeled "Phoebe Carter?" on back of alto part
    - [Lawageela] Lawageela / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([1] sheet); 27 cm. (Box 26, Folder 219)
      Pencil sketch on back
    - [Lord's prayer] The Lords Prayer: For Mixed Voices / Ernest Carter. -- 1903 Dec. 4., 1 manuscript close score ([1] sheet); 30 cm. (Box 26, Folder 220)
      Note: (old)
    - [Lord's prayer] The Lord's Prayer: for Mixed Voices / by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 220)
    - [Lord's prayer] The Lord's Prayer: for Mixed Voices / by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 220)
      Note: (Old)
    - [Lord's prayer] The Lord's Prayer: for Mixed Voices / by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 220)
    - [Lord's prayer] The Lord's Prayer: for Mixed Voices / by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 220)
    - [Lord's prayer] The Lord's Prayer: for Mixed Voices / by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.); 26 cm. (Box 26, Folder 220)
      Note on title page: In C. (Old)
    - [Lord's prayer] The Lord's Prayer: For mixed voices / Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.); 26 cm. (Box 26, Folder 220)
      Note on title page: D (Old)
    - [Lord's prayer] The Lord's Prayer: for Mixed Voices / by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.); 27 cm. (Box 26, Folder 220)
      Note on title page (Old); (C)
    - [Lord's prayer] The Lord's Prayer: For mixed voices a capella / Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.); 26 cm. (Box 26, Folder 220)
      Note on title page: D; (Old)
    - [Lord's prayer] The Lord's Prayer: for Mixed Voices / by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.); 26 cm. (Box 26, Folder 220)
    - [Lord's prayer] The Lord's Prayer: For mixed voices / Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.); 26 cm. (Box 26, Folder 220)
    - [Lord's prayer] The Lord's Prayer: For mixed voices / music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.); 26 cm. (Box 26, Folder 220)
    - [Lord's prayer] The Lord's Prayer: For Four-part Mixed Chorus / Ernest Carter. -- New York: G. Schirmer, c1909., 1 score (6 p.); 26 cm. (Box 26, Folder 220)
      Pl. no.: 20910
      Two copies, with different covers
    - [Lord's prayer] The Lord's Prayer: for Mixed Voices / by Ernest Carter. -- New York: G. Schirmer, c1936., 1 score (6 p.); 27 cm. (Box 26, Folder 220)
      Two copies, one contains Carter's markings
    - [Lovely night] Lovely Night / Ernest Carter. -- 1884., 1 manuscript close score ([1] sheet); 23 x 26 cm. (Box 26, Folder 221)
      Note: Fall of 1884
    - [Mammy's growin' ole; arr.] Mammy's Growin' Ole: For mixed voices with piano accompaniment / Music by Ernest Carter; Words by James D. Corrothers., 1 manuscript score ([4] p.); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 222)
    - [Mammy's growin' ole; arr.] Mammy's Growin' Ole: For female voices with piano accompaniment / Music by Ernest Carter; Words by James D. Corrothers., 1 manuscript score ([4] p.); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 222)
    - [Mammy's growin' ole; arr. (Sketches)], [1] sheet of music; 33 cm. (Box 26, Folder 222)
    - [Mary's little wise man] Mary's Little Wise Man / E.T. Carter '88. -- New York: G. Schirmer, c1902, 1 close score ([1] p.); 27 cm. (Box 26, Folder 223)
      For male voices, unacc.
      Pl. no.: 18460
      On top of p.: 18460
    - [Memorial hymn to General Armstrong] Memorial hymn to General Armstrong / Music by Ernest Trow Carter; Words by Alice M. Bacon. -- 1893., 1 close score ([1] sheet); 27 cm. (Box 26, Folder 223)
    - [My soul doth magnify the Lord (Sketches)], [1] sheet of music; 27 x 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 223)
      Title from first line of text
    - [New Medley] New Medley., 4 manuscript parts; 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 223)
      Includes tenors I-II, basses I-II
      First bass part entitled: Campus Favorites
    - [O li'l lamb] O Li'l Lamb: (A Hymn) / Music by Ernest Carter; Words by Paul Lawrence Dunbar. ca. 1898 Sep., 1 manuscript score ([1] folded sheet); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 223)
    - [O li'l lamb. Text] [1] sheet; 16 cm., manuscript in Carter's hand in pencil (Box 26, Folder 223)
      Words by Paul Lawrence Dunbar
    - [Orange, white, and blue] The Orange, White and Blue / Music by Ernest Carter; Words by John B. Price., 1 manuscript score (3 p.); 30 cm. (Box 26, Folder 223)
      For chorus (SATB) and piano
    - [Orange, white and blue. Text] The orange, white and blue / John G. Pine. -- 1915 Jun. 24., [1] sheet; 27 cm. (Box 26, Folder 223)
    - [Our Ping-Pong Banjo Club] Our Ping-Pong Banjo Club: male voices / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 35 cm. (Box 26, Folder 223)
      Piano accompaniment
    - [Out of the depths] Out of the Depths: Anthem for mixed voices with Organ Accompaniment / [music by] Ernest Carter; [words by] James Montgomery. -- New York; Chicago: Tullar Meredith Co., c1908., 1 score (4 p.); 27 cm. (Box 26, Folder 224)
    - [Out of the depths] Out of the Depths: Anthem for Mixed Voices with Organ Accompaniment / Music by Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1908 Mar., 1 manuscript score ([4] p.); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 224)
      Note on bottom of title page: OK Mch '08
    - [Out of the depths] Out of the Depths of War / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 27 x 33 cm. (Box 26, Folder 224)
      For chorus (SSAB) and organ
    - [Out of the depths] Out of the Depths: Anthem for mixed voices with organ accompaniment / Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 224)
    - [Out of the depths] Out of the Depths: Anthem for mixed voices with organ accompaniment / Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([3] p.); 35 cm. (Box 26, Folder 224)
      Note on title page: Old
    - [Out of the depths] Out of the Depths: Anthem for mixed voices / Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([4] p.); 35 cm. (Box 26, Folder 224)
      manuscript in ink in W.M.D.'s hand
    - [Out of the depths (Sketches)] Out of the Depths / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([4] p.); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 224)
      Note on first p.: 2 hrs.
    - [Out of the depths. Text] Out of the depths: Sacred Text to Song "Verzweiflung" / Ernest Carter., [1] sheet; 27 cm. (Box 26, Folder 224)
    - [Peace, good will] Peace, good will: Christmas anthem: for mixed voices / Words & Music by Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1918 Nov. 20., 1 manuscript score (7 p.) + 4 parts; 35 cm. (Box 26, Folder 225)
      Includes soprano, alto, tenor, and bass parts
      Date from bottom left corner of first page
    - [Peace, good will] Christmas anthem: for mixed voices and organ / Words and music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (9 p.); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 225)
    - [Peace, good will] Peace, Good Will: Christmas Carol: for Mixed Voices and Organ / Words and Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (7 p.); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 225)
    - [Peace, good will. Text] Peace, good will: Christmas carol / Ernest T. Carter. -- 1918 Oct. 27., [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 26, Folder 225)
      Two other typescript copies laid in
      Four typescript sheets with program and prologue for a "Christmas Festival" laid in
    - [Peace I leave with you] Peace I leave with you: For Mixed Voices / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([1] sheet); 14 x 22 cm. (Box 26, Folder 226)
      Note above title: To Harry Gilbert and his Choir of the Fifth Avenue Presbyterian Church of New York
    - [Peace I leave with you] Peace I Leave With You / Ernest T. Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([1] sheet); 26 cm. (Box 26, Folder 226)
    - [Psalm 121. Text], [1] sheet; 9 x 21 cm. (Box 26, Folder 226)
    - [Recessional] Recessional / [music by] Ernest Carter; [words by] Rudyard Kipling. -- 1946., 1 manuscript score ([4] p.); 36 cm. (Box 26, Folder 227)
      For male voices, organ, and trumpet obligato
      Pencil sketches laid in
    - [Recessional] Recessional: For Male Voices / Music by Ernest Carter; Words by Rudyard Kipling., 1 manuscript part (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 26, Folder 227)
      Negative photocopy, as well as four positive photocopies (two marked for sopranos and altos), laid in
    - [Recessional] Recessional: For Male Voices and Organ with Trumpet Obligato / Words by Rudyard Kipling; Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (11 p.) + 1 part; 32 cm. (Box 26, Folder 227)
    - [Ring out, ye wedding bells] Ring Out, Ye Wedding Bells: Song for mixed voices with organ accompaniment / By Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score (2 p.); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 228)
    - [Said the prince unto the maiden] Said the prince unto the Maiden / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([1] folded sheet); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 234)
      With: Through the wood (Choral Works)
    - [See, the Conqueror mounts in triumph] See, the Conqueror Mounts in Triumph: Easter Hymn / Ernest T. Carter. -- c1891., 1 close score ([1] sheet); 28 cm. (Box 27, Folder 229)
      Block with engraved plate laid in
    - [Senior song] Senior song: (March): For Chorus of Women's Voices with Piano Accompaniment / Words by Rita Robinson; Music by Ernest Carter. -- c1924., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 33 cm. (Box 27, Folder 230)
      On title page: Dedicated to The Masters School
    - [Senior song] Senior Song: (March): For Chorus of Women's Voices with Piano Accompaniment / Words by Rita Robinson; Music by Ernest Carter. -- c1924., 1 score ([2] p.); 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 230)
    - [Sons of Nassau; arr.] Sons of Nassau / Reichner-Carter; arr. for male voices by Ernest Carter. -- 1917 Nov. 5., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 33 cm. (Box 27, Folder 231)
      For unacc. male chorus
    - [Sons of Nassau; arr.] Sons of Nassau / Music by Ernest T. Carter, '88, [and] L. Irving Reichner; Words by L. Irving Reichner., 1 close score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 27, Folder 231)
      Three copies with pencil corrections by Carter, one copy with note: (Edition of May 1919) latest and best; For male voices a capella
    - [Sons of Nassau; arr.] Sons of Nassau / Music by Ernest T. Carter, '88, [and] L. Irving Reichner, '94; Words by L. Irving Reichner, '94., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 27, Folder 231)
      Photocopy
    - [Sons of Nassau. Text] Sons of Nassau., [1] sheet; 16 cm. (Box 27, Folder 231)
    - [Spoiled Willie] Spoiled Willie: or Give me more sugar on my mush / Words + Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 36 cm. (Box 27, Folder 232)
      For baritone solo and chorus (TTBB), unacc.
    - [Spoiled Willie] 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 34 cm., Holograph in ink (Box 27, Folder 232)
    - [Spoiled Willie] 4 manuscript parts; 27 cm., Holographs in ink (Box 27, Folder 232)
      Includes parts for tenor I-II, and bass I-II
    - [Spoiled Willie (Sketches)] If Willie only would come back / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 24 x 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 232)
    - [Spoiled Willie; arr.] Spoiled Willie: or Give me more sugar on my mush / Words + Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 36 cm. (Box 27, Folder 232)
      For baritone solo and chorus (TTBB)
    - [Spoiled Willie; arr.], 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 232)
    - [Spoiled Willie; arr.] If Willie only would come back / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 24 x 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 232)
      For solo voice and chorus (TTBB)
    - [Spoiled Willie; arr.], 4 manuscript parts; 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 232)
      For tenors I-II and basses I-II
    - [Spoiled Willie; arr.] Spoiled Willie: For Male Quartet / Words + Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 232)
      For chorus (TTBB) unacc.
    - [Spoiled Willie; arr.] Spoiled Willie: For Male Quartet / Words and Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 232)
    - [Spoiled Willie; arr.] Spoiled Willie: For Male Quartet / Words and Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 232)
    - [Spoiled Willie; arr.] Spoiled Willie: (comic male quartet) / Words and Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 232)
    - [Spoiled Willie; arr.] Spoiled Willie: (For Male Quartet) / Words and Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 232)
    - [Spoiled Willie. Text] Spoiled Willie: Comic Male Quartet / Words & Music by Ernest Carter., 4 sheets; 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 232)
      Another incomplete typescript copy laid in
    - [Steps Song] Steps Song: Male Voices / Words and Music by Ernest Carter, '88. -- c1894., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.); 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 233)
      Photocopy with manuscript additions
      manuscript tenor I-II and bass I-II parts to Integer Vitae laid in
      Note on bottom of score: The closing chord of the last verse should die away and swell again into the opening chord of Integer Vitae in the same key, one verse of which should be sung by a concealed quartet, when possible
    - [Steps song] Steps Song., 1 manuscript close score ([1] sheet); 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 233)
    - [Steps song] Steps Song., 1 manuscript close score ([1] sheet); 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 233)
    - [Team that plays to-day. Text] The team that plays to-day / Ernest Carter. ca. 1905 Jun., [1] sheet; 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 234)
      Words to a choral work?
      Note on old envelope said score copied 1905 Jun.
    - [Through the wood] Through the wood / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 234)
      For soprano, alto, and piano
      With: Said the prince unto the Maiden / Ernest Carter [song]
    - [Tigers are coming] The Tigers are Coming: (Bugle March) / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript part; 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 234)
      Voice part only
    - [Tioga Lodge] Tioga Lodge / Words + Music by Ernest Carter. -- 1921., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.) + 1 part; 26 cm. (Box 27, Folder 235)
      Holographs, score signed, in pencil
      Alto part only
    - [Tioga lodge] Tioga Lodge: For Mixed Voices / Words and Music by Ernest Carter., 1 close score ([1] sheet); 26 cm. (Box 27, Folder 235)
    - [Tioga lodge. Text] Tioga lodge: (To the music of "Steps Song") / Ernest Carter. -- 1921 Aug., [1] sheet; 14 x 20 cm. (Box 27, Folder 235)
    - [Toast of degrees] A Toast of Degrees / By Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([1] sheet) + 4 parts; 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 236)
      Holographs, score signed, in ink, text in the parts in typescript
    - [Toast of degrees] A Toast of Degrees / By Ernest Carter., 1 close score ([1] sheet); 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 236)
      Two copies of the score with an alternative text laid in (To our "Old Conductor" ...)
    - [Toast of degrees. Text], [1] sheet; 21 cm. (Box 27, Folder 236)
      Two copies each of orignal and alternative verse (To our "Old Conductor"...)
      Seven typescript and holograph texts with both texts laid in
    - [Tower song] Tower song: For Female Voices / Music by Ernest Carter / Words by Clarissa Jacobus., 1 manuscript score ([2] p.); 32 cm. (Box 27, Folder 237)
      For chorus (SSAA) and piano
    - [Tower song] Tower song: For Female Voices / Words by Clarissa Jacobus; Music by Ernest Carter. -- c1923., 1 score ([2] p.); 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 237)
    - [Tower song] Tower song: For Women's Voices / Words by Clarissa Jacobus; Music by Ernest Carter. -- c1923., 1 score ([3] p.); 26 cm. (Box 27, Folder 237)
    - [Tower song; arr.] Tower Song / Ernest Carter. -- 1923., 1 manuscript score ([3] sheets); 35 cm. (Box 27, Folder 237)
      Arr. for voices, solo violin, clarinet, violins I, violins II (ad. lib.), violoncello, and bass
    - [Trinity sevenfold amen] Trinity Amen / Music by Ernest Carter. -- c1926., 1 manuscript close score ([1] sheet); 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 238)
      Typescript note pasted on
    - [Trinity sevenfold amen] Trinity Sevenfold Amen: For Mixed Voices / Music by Ernest Carter. -- c1927., 1 manuscript close score ([1] sheet); 29 cm. (Box 27, Folder 238)
      Two copies, one with "Sevenfold" added to title
    - [Trinity sevenfold amen; arr.] Trinity Sevenfold Amen: (For Male Voices) / Music by Ernest Carter; arr. by Harry Burleigh. -- 1929., 1 manuscript close score ([1] sheet); 25 x 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 238)
      manuscript in pencil with last measure addition by Carter
    - [Venlan] Venlan / Harmonized by E.T. Carter. -- 1896 May 7., 1 close score ([1] sheet); 23 cm. (Box 27, Folder 239)
      Words by Addison
    - [We give Thee thanks this day. Text] E.T.C. -- 1939 Nov. 23., [1] sheet; 4 x 22 cm. (Box 27, Folder 239)
      Two copies, one signed
    - [Wee star lullaby] Lullaby / Ernest Carter. -- 1899 Apr. 23., 1 manuscript close score ([1] sheet); 17 x 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 240)
    - [Wee star lullaby] Wee Star Lullaby: for mixed voices / Words + Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([1] sheet) + 4 parts; 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 240)
    - [Wee star lullaby] Wee Star Lullaby: Mixed Voices: C / Words and Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.); 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 240)
    - [Wee star lullaby] Wee Star Lullaby: (Mixed Voices): (D) / Words and Music by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.); 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 240)
    - [Wee star lullaby. Text] Wee Star Lullaby / Ernest Carter., [1] sheet; 22 cm. (Box 27, Folder 240)
      Another typescript text laid in
    - [Wine of Jurancon] The Wine of Jurancon: For Male Chorus: The Padres / Music by Ernest Carter; Words from the French of Charles Coran; Translated by H.W. Longfellow. -- ca. 1907-1909., 1 manuscript score ([4] p.); 35 cm. (Box 27, Folder 241)
      For chorus (TTBB), unacc.
      On bottom of p.: O.K. Nov. 22/07-March 6/09; O.F. Nov. 14/07
    - [Wine of Jurancon] The Wine of Jurancon: For Male Chorus / Words from the French of Charles Coran; Translated by H.W. Longfellow / Music by Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1907 Nov. 14-22., 1 manuscript score (5 p.); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 241)
      On bottom of title page: OK Nov. 22/07; O.F. Nov 14/07
    - [Wine of Jurancon] The Wine of Jurancon: For Male Chorus / Music by Ernest Carter; Words by H.W. Longfellow. -- ca. 1907-1909., 1 manuscript score (pp. 148-149); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 241)
      Notes on title page: omit in Jones version May 5/31; OK Nov. 22/07 March 6/09; O.F. Nov. 19/1907
      From the Blonde Donna?
    - [Wine of Jurancon] The Wine of Jurancon: Glee for Male Voices / Music by Ernest T. Carter; Words by Longfellow., 1 manuscript score ([5] p.); 35 cm. (Box 27, Folder 241)
      Incomplete, includes tenor I part only
      Written for and sung by the Princeton College Glee Club
    - [Wine of Jurancon] The Wine of Jurancon: For Male [voices] / Words From the French of Chas. Coran; translated by H.W. Longfellow; Music by Ernest Carter. -- ca. 1907-1909., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.) + 4 parts; 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 241)
      On bottom of title page: OK Nov 22/07 March 6/09
    - [Wine of Jurancon] The Wine of Jurancon: (Male Quartet) / Music by Ernest Carter; Words by Longfellow., 1 manuscript close score ([4] p.); 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 241)
    - [Wine of Jurancon] The Wine of Jurancon: For Male Chorus / Music by Ernest Carter; Words by H.W. Longfellow., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 241)
    - [Wine of Jurancon] The Wine of Jurancon / E.T.C. -- ca. 1888., 4 manuscript parts; 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 241)
      Includes parts for tenors I-II and basses I-II
      Pencil note by Carter on tenor I part: Sung by Quartet of Princeton Glee Club, Commencement 1888 - Introduced in Blonde Donna
    - [Wine of Jurancon. Text] The Wine of Jurancon / Henry W. Longfellow., [1] sheet; 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 241)
    - [Wine of Jurancon. Text] The wine of Jurancon / From the French of Charles Coran; Translated by Henry W. Longfellow., [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 27, Folder 241)
    - [Winter serenade] A Winter Serenade: for Male Voices with Mandolin Club Accompaniment / by Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript score ([8] p.); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 242)
      For chorus (TTBB), flute, clarinet, cornet, mandolins I-II, mandola, guitars I-II, violins I-II, viola, and violoncello
    - [Winter serenade] A Winter Serenade: (Male Quartet) / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([2] p.); 28 cm. (Box 27, Folder 242)
      Note on first p.: used in Blonde Donna
    - [Witherspoon march] Witherspoon March / Ernest Carter., 1 manuscript close score ([4] p.); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 243)
    - [Witherspoon march] Witherspoon March., 1 manuscript close score ([4] p.); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 243)
    - [Unidentified piece, mixed voices (Sketches)], [1] sheet of music; 13 x 23 cm. (Box 27, Folder 244)
      Torn in half
  - Songs, I.E
    - [As the billows] As the billows / music by Ernest Carter; words by Marie Corelli: from "A Romance of Two Worlds.", 1 manuscript score (6 p.); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 245)
      Holograph signed, in ink
      On title page: B
    - [As the billows] As the billows / music by Ernest Carter; words by Marie Corelli; from ("A romance at two worlds"). -- 1907 Dec. 4., 1 manuscript score (4 p.); 35 cm. (Box 27, Folder 245)
      On title page: A; OK Dec 4/07
    - [As the billows] As the billows / music by Ernest Carter; words by Marie Corelli; (From "A Romance of Two Worlds"). -- 1907 Dec. 5., 1 manuscript score (4 p.); 35 cm. (Box 27, Folder 245)
    - [As the billows] As the billows / music by Ernest Carter; words by Marie Corelli; (From "A Romance of Two Worlds")., 1 manuscript score (4 p.); 35 cm. (Box 27, Folder 245)
    - [As the billows. Text] As the billows: or I dare to love thee / words by Marie Corelli (From "A Romance of Two Worlds"); Music by Ernest Carter., [1] sheet; 27 cm. (Box 27, Folder 245)